Guide to the Anthony Caputi papers,1956-1989
Anthony Caputi papers,1956-1989
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Anthony Caputi papers, 1952-1989
14/12/3593
Anthony Francis, Caputi 1924-
3 cubic feet.
Correspondence, Printed Materials
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Includes lecture notes, correspondence, and course material on various drama courses. taught.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Professor of English and Comparative Literature, Cornell University from 1956-1991, serving some time as chair in both departments.
He completed his B.A. in English at the University of Buffalo, followed by his M.A. in 1951. In 1956 he received his PhD from Cornell. He received a Fulbright Fellowship at Oxford University in 1954-1955, a senior Fulbright Fellowship, along with a Guggenheim Fellowship to Italy in 1964-1965 and in 1971-1972 he held a National Endowment for the Humanities Fellowship.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Includes lecture notes, correspondence, and course material on various drama courses. taught.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Caputi, Anthony Francis,1924-; Cornell University.English Dept.; Cornell University.--Faculty.
Subjects:
English literature--Study and teaching.; College teachers.; Drama--Study and teaching.
Form and Genre Terms:
Photographs.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Course Material
  - Greek Drama - Dramatic Production (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Sophocles (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Aeschylus (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Euripides (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Aristophanes (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Roman Theatre and Playwrights, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Tragedy - Criticism, 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Christopher Marlowe (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Pre-Elizabethan Drama (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Contemporaries and Followers of Shakespeare to 1642 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Ben Jonson 1572-1637 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Webster (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Fore-runners of Shakespeare (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Shakespeare: Introductory, 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Shakespeare: Comedies (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Intro. to Drama, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Ben Jonson 1572-1637 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Macbeth (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Coriolanus (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Othello / Lear (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Comedy Seminar, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Restoration Drama and Playwrights (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - 18th Century Drama (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - European Drama 1630-1900, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Miscellaneous Notes (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Shakespeare: Histories (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Magic (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Brecht (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Pirandello (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Modern Drama (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Modern Drama - Course Plan, Exams, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Modernism (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Brecht (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Noel Coward (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Chekhov, Strindberg (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Miller (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous Modernism, 1983-1984 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Representative English Dramas, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Assorted Modern Playwrights (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Shaw, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Irish Drama (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Comedy / Tragedy (2 Lectures) (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Four Modern Playwrights, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - 19th Century Drama (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - English 127 - Shakespeare, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Shakespeare - English 427, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - English 270.1 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Medieval / Spanish World Drama, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Pinder (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Dramatic Criticism, 1965-1966 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - American Humor, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Three Ages of Theatre (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - O'Neill (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Greek Comedy (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - English 382, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence Relating to Masterworks of World Drama (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Course Evaluations, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - English 272.1 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Notes, Correspondence, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Pudsey (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Renaissance (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - English 564 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Comedy (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - English 201 Survey, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - English 147 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - English 149.2 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - English 151.9 - Shakespeare and the Moderns, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - World Literature (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Course in the Methods of Research, 1969-1970 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Quizzes, Exams, and Odd Quotations (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Talks, Papers, etc., 1962 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Reports, etc., 1968 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - D.C. Heath Correspondence, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Labor Liberal Arts Program, 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Class Lists, Odd Records, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Photographs (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Modern Drama (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - English 388-389 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Word Processor Invoices, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Job Placement (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Stratford, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Dramatic Literature, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - English 384 / 281 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - World Drama - Exams, Quizzes, 1952-1987 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Shakespeare - Quizzes, Outlines, 1953-1987 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - British Drama - Quizzes, Prelims, 1959-1980 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Pierre Corneille (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - History of the English Language / Old English Literature (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Literature of the Middle Ages: Religious and Secular (Metrical Romances) to Chaucer (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Poetry (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Geoffrey Chaucer: 1340-1400 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Literature of the Middle Ages: The Period of Great Individual Writers (Langland, Gower, Pearl Poet) (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Edmund Spenser: 1552-1599 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Renaissance Prose (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Renaissance Criticism (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - The Sonnet (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - 17th Century Poetry (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - 17th Century Prose (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - John Milton (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - The Restoration (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - English 470, 1961-1962 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Augustan Age (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Age of Johnson (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Pre-Romantic Movement (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Romanticism - Wordsworth and Coleridge (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Byron, Shelley, Keats (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - 19th Century Novel (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Victorian Poetry (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - 19th Century Prose (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - The Pre-Raphaelites (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Modern Poetry (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - American Literature (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Md. American Novel (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Modern Novel (Box 3, Folder 30)